Lenny Githenya

lennygith@gmail.com

+254705761133

linkedin.com/in/lenny-githenya

https://tinyurl.com/LennyPortfolio

Summary

Fullstack developer with 4 years of experience as an API (back-end), Front-end, Dev-Ops and IoT developer.

My professional skills include C# (dotnet), Node JS, React JS, DevOps, Database administration (Microsoft SQL), IoT prototyping and development, Windows & Linux scripting, and Enterprise system support.

A significant highlight of my career is the re-development of the tax payment systems between NCBA Bank Kenya and KRA which not only saves the bank an estimated 10 million Kenyan Shillings in fines per month but also earned an overall service rating of 95%, which is the highest by a bank within the country.

My contributions in my current role have led to me being the first inductee on NCBA Group's IT Wall of Fame

Experience

API Developer

NCBA Group

Jun 2022 - Present (1 year 8 months)

My primary responsibilities included C# development, Front-end development (Bootstrap, React), DevOps, and Culture and training champion for the department.

Below are significant achievements:

- * First inductee into NCBA Group's IT Wall of Fame. The award is in recognition of the superb service and technological solutions offered.
- * Redevelopment and modernization of cross-channel middleware, increasing availability of services from 80% uptime per calendar day to 97%. This involved microservice architecture, use of DevOps, and hybrid-cloud environments.

The project has led to an estimated cost savings of 12 million per month.

* Development of Tax integrations for Kenya (KRA), Rwanda (RRA) and Uganda(URA).

The KRA service earned a distinguished service monitoring score of 95% from KRA, the highest from a bank in the country.

The RRA service efficiency improvement by a factor of 1500% has led to the retention of clients transacting an estimated

- * Overhauling NCBA's Open banking Mobile transfer service in compliance with new CBK regulations. I also created a new Front end to better fit NCBA's digital brand guidelines.
- * Training on organization culture and systems leading to my appointment as the Culture and Training Champion in the department.

Information Technology Intern

Teachers service Commission - Kenya

Mar 2022 - May 2022 (3 months)

My primary responsibilities included Systems support, hardware support, Active Directory management, and technical and end-user training.

Below are notable achievements:

- * Part of the team responsible for Active Directory enrollment for 3000 staff members at headquarters
- * Inducted as one of 3 trainers due to exemplary knowledge of systems processes and communication skill
- * First-level support with an average turnaround time of 24 minutes (expected turnaround time was 1 hour)
- * Hardware and network support for 3,500 staff members within Nairobi county



Minet Kenya

May 2021 - Mar 2022 (11 months)

My primary responsibilities included Systems development, IoT development, Chatbot development, and Systems, Network and Hardware support.

Below are substantial achievements:

* Development of a prototype for an accident tracking and reporting platform.

Not only was I the sole Full-stack web developer, but I also came up with the hardware unit prototype and designed the production schematic templates.

* Developed the Minet Insurance Broker Chatbot platform for the web and WhatsApp.

The Chatbot remarkably improved accessibility and provided a 24/7 customer service channel with utilities such as policy purchases also being availed outside office hours.

* Software/Network/Hardware support with an average daily case resolution count of 17 (the average for the department being 12).



Intern

Minet Kenya

Apr 2019 - Aug 2019 (5 months)

My primary responsibilities included Chatbot development, Data analysis, and Systems, Network and Hardware support.

Below are outstanding achievements:

* Developed prototype for Minet Insurance Broker's chatbot.

The prototype was later deployed to production when I returned after completing my undergraduate studies.

- * Data analysis and cleanup for transactional details using Microsoft Power BI
- * Software/Network/Hardware support.

Education



Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Bsc Mathematics and Computer Science, Applied Mathematics 2016 - 2021

Licenses & Certifications

- (A) Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp
- Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4 Coursera Course
 Certificates
 Z7N5N337HEZG
- (A) JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures freeCodeCamp
- Introduction to IoT Cisco Networking Academy
- **Google Cloud Developer Scholarship (Cloud Track)** Google Developers Group 705FD2FECC7F0E9

Skills

Full-Stack Development • .NET Core • SQL • Node.js • React.js • Version Control • terminal scripting • Technical Support • Software Development • DevOps

Honors & Awards

TT Wall of Fame - NCBA Group

Aug 2023

Recognition of outstanding service with regards to technological solutions, customer experience, and professionalism.